miraheze.org 2019-12-31

# Privacy Policy - Miraheze Meta

_**This page documents a Miraheze global policy** , this policy follows consensus and/or Staff guidelines. All Miraheze users should follow it, and changes made to it should be discussed on the talk page._

Miraheze is committed to preserving your privacy and being transparent about how we use information collected through Miraheze.org (the "Website") and any other applications, functionality, or services offered by Miraheze (collectively with the Website, the "Services"). This Privacy Policy describes how Miraheze uses, collects, and shares information collected through the Services. By using the Services, you agree to and accept the practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

We may modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will post changes on this page so be sure to check back regularly. We will also notify you by posting an announcement on the Website so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, it is disclosed. Continuing to use our Services after any changes have been posted, constitutes your acceptance of any modifications to the Terms. 

## 1\. Contributions

**1.1 Public Content.** In general, all content (pages, images, files, etc.) on Miraheze is public, including any contributions made by Miraheze community members. The history of every edit to content made through the Services is publicly displayed and retained indefinitely by Miraheze. Even if an article is "deleted," a website administrator or volunteer may still see what was removed from public view. Aside from the rare times when Miraheze is required to delete editing-history in response to a court order or legal process, there is no guarantee that permanent deletion will occur. 

**1.2 Individual Contributions.** If you contribute or edit content on through the Services ("Contributions"), your Contributions will be visible to the public and may show up in search results of third-party search engines. If you have registered an account with Miraheze, your Contributions will be associated with your username. If you have not registered with Miraheze, your Contributions will be associated with your IP Address. 

**1.3 Private Wikis.** Some wikis may be marked as private, which means that Contributions therein are not normally released to the general public. Miraheze personnel and a small number of vetted volunteers have access to content on private wikis as part of their role in assisting to provide our Services. Access to content on private wikis is granted or revoked by the creators and administrators of these wikis. Be aware that the wiki administrators can restrict your access to Contributions you have made on a private wiki, or even to make the entire wiki public content. 

## 2\. Information Collected by Miraheze

As part of the Services, we may collect the following types of information from you when you use the Services ("User Information"): 

**2.1 Registration Information.** In order to access certain portions of the Services you must complete a registration form. In this registration form, we collect certain personal information, such as your email address, username and password. Your email address will remain private, unless you choose to post it on public facing portions of the Services, such as your profile page or the Contributors Page. Please use discretion on what you choose to post on public facing portions of the Services, as it will be available to the public and may show up in search results of third-party engines. 

**2.2 Username.** You will also be asked to create a username, which will be used to identify when you are logged onto the Services, and to identify your Contributions to the Services. Again, your username will be visible to the public, and may show up in search results of third-party search engines. 

**2.3 Optional user information:** As a registered user, you may choose to share more details publicly. You may provide your name, a personal website, share your email address, and talk about yourself on your profile page. Please use discretion on what you choose to post on public facing portions of the Services, as it will be available to the public and may show up in search results of third-party engines. If provided, your name may be used to identify your Contributions to the Service, and may be used by third parties as a means to attribute your contributions. 

**2.4 Usage Information.** Miraheze may collect certain usage data, such as your IP address, URL request, browser type, and the date and time of a request. Miraheze may use cookies (as further described below) or other automated mechanisms to collect this information and may collect this information on an aggregate or individual basis. Miraheze uses this information for statistical purposes to help administer, manage and improve the Services, prevent abuse, analyse trends, and to tailor your user experience. In addition, Miraheze may use anonymised usage statistics that may be derived from this information for marketing, research or reporting purposes. Miraheze honours the Do Not Track header and does not collect analytics data from users who have enabled this feature on their browser. 

**2.5 IP Address.** Contributions made by unregistered users will be publicly identified by that user’s IP Address. 

## 3\. Information Collected by Hosted Wikis

While this policy applies to all wikis hosted by Miraheze, the operators of the Hosted Wikis may collect additional User Information. Miraheze does not retain any of this data. Any additional User Information collected by a Hosted Wiki must be described on the privacy policy page of that wiki and must be collected in compliance with applicable law. If you learn that a wiki is collecting data beyond the scope of its privacy policy or in violation of the law, please discontinue using that wiki and inform Miraheze immediately. 

## 4\. Cookies

Cookies are small files that Miraheze can send to your browser for storage on your computer. Cookies make using the Services easier by saving your status and preferences and refreshing them every time you use the Services. For instance, Miraheze may use cookies to recognise you when you return to the Services so that you do not have to resubmit your log-in credentials. In order to clear this logon information, for example if using a public terminal, you should log out of your account. While many browsers allow you to change your settings in order to refuse cookies or to be alerted when cookies are being sent, Miraheze recommends that you leave cookies enabled, as disabling cookies may prevent you from using and may interfere with some functionality of the Services. 

Cookies are not required to browse Miraheze, but are technically required for some features. Miraheze uses cookies for: 

  * Maintaining logged in status, using an account, and setting preferences; or
  * Ensuring that once you have read the cookie warning required by UK law, you no longer see this notice; or
  * Gathering Usage Information for statistical purposes. This may be disabled by setting your browser to send a Do Not Track header. Use of this data is subject to the restrictions of Section 7 below.

No personally identifiable information will be disclosed to any third party solely and directly by your use of cookies. 

## 5\. Archiving

Miraheze may retain User Information collected through the Services indefinitely for restorative, archival, or research purposes. Your personal information is kept private and stored securely until a time it is no longer required or has no use. 

Miraheze retains individual Usage Information for 90 days, after which it is deleted. 

## 6\. Email Communications

Miraheze may send you emails containing Miraheze-related news, products, offers, surveys or promotions. You may also receive notification emails from Miraheze to inform you of changes in the Services, new service offerings or other information related to your use of the Services. If you do not want to receive promotional emails from Miraheze, please visit your User Preferences page or follow the opt-out instructions contained in email messages you receive from us. However, please note that, even if you choose not to receive marketing emails from Miraheze, you will continue to receive all emails related to your use of the Services (e.g. those regarding forgotten user passwords) from Miraheze. Controls to set which emails you receive from Miraheze are in the Preferences page. 

In addition to automated messages sent by the Services, users with verified email addresses may wish to communicate with each other. By default, if you have a verified email address, other users may use a Special page ("EmailUser") to send messages to you and vice versa. When you use EmailUser to send a message, Miraheze will send an email to the recipient of your choice which includes your email address and the content you chose to send. Your email address is not revealed when others contact you. EmailUser functionality may be enabled or disabled on the Preferences page. 

## 7\. Sharing of Information with Third Parties

Generally, Miraheze does not share User Information with third parties without your consent. Nonetheless, in order to maximize your user experience on the Services, the following individuals or entities may have access to User Information: 

**7.1 Miraheze Personnel.** Miraheze personnel and a small number of vetted volunteers may have access to User Information as necessary for Miraheze to operate its business and to provide you the Services. 

**7.2 Third Party Service Providers.** Miraheze may share User Information with its third-party service providers as necessary for those third party service providers to provide services to Miraheze. 

**7.3 Business Transfers.** If Miraheze is acquired by or Miraheze otherwise transfers and/or sells substantially all its assets to another company, Miraheze will transfer any User Information it has in its possession to the other company as part of the sale or transfer of the company or assets. 

**7.4 Protection of Miraheze and Others.** We may share User Information when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to comply with a court order; to comply with applicable law; to comply with a subpoena from a third party; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Miraheze, our employees, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection. 

**7.5 Data Analysis.** Miraheze may use, transfer, and share aggregated, anonymous data derived from User Information with wiki administrators, researchers, journalists, funders and other third parties that Miraheze may choose to work with. This data will not include any personally identifiable information. 

## 8\. Children

Miraheze does not operate Services that are targeted at people under 13 years of age, and does not collect personally identifiable information. If you are a parent or guardian and become aware that your child has been using the Services, please let us know and we will remove your child’s information. 

## 9\. Transfer of Information Across Borders

Your information may be transferred to, and maintained on, servers and databases located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as your jurisdiction. Please be advised that we may transfer your information to and from any state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction, and process it in the United States, the Netherlands, or elsewhere. By using the Services, you consent to any such transfer of your information. 

## 10\. Copies, Amendments, and Erasure of Personally Identifiable Information

You have a right to a digital copy of all personally identifiable information (PII) stored about you by Miraheze. You also have the right that we correct any PII that Miraheze has collected or displays on the Service. 

Additionally, you have a right to request erasure of PII stored by Miraheze. Wiki Contributions are typically not subject to this clause, as they are governed by the applicable content license contract under which you submitted the data. In particular, you should be aware that most Creative Commons licenses require that Miraheze provide attribution of the author of the content. 

In order to make any of these requests, please follow our Data Request Process. 

## 11\. Security Notifications

You have the right to be notified of any security breach at Miraheze which exposes your personal information. Miraheze will make public disclosures of security breaches that we uncover on the Website. If we determine that a breach of the Services has revealed personally identifiable information of a large number of users, Miraheze will announce the issue by a notice on all wikis. If it is likely that your information has been hacked, and you have provided Miraheze with your email, Miraheze will send email notifications on the breach to you. 

Effective Date of this Privacy Policy 

  * This Privacy Policy is effective as of 2016-12-10.
  * This policy was last revised on 2019-12-30.

## Previous versions

You can browse previous version of privacy policy in the following links. 

  * Privacy Policy (2018-06-04 ~ 2019-12-30)
  * Privacy Policy (2016-12-10 ~ 2018-05-25)

In the event of any differences in meaning between the original English version and a translation, the original English version takes precedence.
